<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aviation on Ashley Grealish</title>
    <link>https://grealish.co.uk/categories/aviation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aviation on Ashley Grealish</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://grealish.co.uk/categories/aviation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most from your PPL lessons</title>
      <link>https://grealish.co.uk/blog/getting-the-most-from-ppl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grealish.co.uk/blog/getting-the-most-from-ppl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-the-right-school&#34;&gt;Find the right school&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grealish.co.uk/img/airfield.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Airfield&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there will only be one school within any reasonable distance from you, so you you have little choice. But, if you do have choice you may want to visit a number of schools and do a trial lesson. When visiting, you can answer any questions you have. I would recommend you ask about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Costs&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can they do a package deal for the minimum 45 hours&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Or, if you prefer can they accept a pay-as-you-go arrangement so that can can pay for each lesson when you can afford them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What extra costs do they expect for ground school, equipment, landing fees, health checks &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Availability&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How many instructors do they have&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When are they most busy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Does this align with your schedule&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sustainability&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What aircraft do they use&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can you do any training on an electric aircraft&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can you supplement your training with simulator time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Weather&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What does the typical year look like at this airfield&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In summer and in winter, what % of flight lessons get cancelled due to poor weather.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can you speak with a current or former student?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Asking these questions will ensure you find the right school for you. Finding a school that matches your needs is the most impactful thing you can do to get the most from your PPL. But once you&amp;rsquo;ve found the right school, there is more you can do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Carbon Impact of a Private Pilot Licence (PPL)</title>
      <link>https://grealish.co.uk/blog/ppl-carbon-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grealish.co.uk/blog/ppl-carbon-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-influences-the-carbon-emissions&#34;&gt;What influences the carbon emissions?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grealish.co.uk/img/cessna-172.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cessna 172&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-much-you-fly&#34;&gt;How much you fly?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The standard UK PPL mandates a minimum 45 hours of flight time. Many students will complete their PPL within this minimum number of hours, but others will take more time. Clearly, the more hours you spend in the air, the more carbon emissions will be generated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-you-fly&#34;&gt;What you fly&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most flight schools will use small, fairly fuel effecient aircraft. The Cessna 152 is a small 2 seater that is great to learn in. The Cessna 172 and the Piper PA28 are also common 4-seater options, for those who feel the 152 is too small. Check what options your school has and ask about fuel efficiency of their fleet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
